today we are making a simple lemon peel
cardigan
and i used just under five skeins of
bernat softie cotton which is a light
three weight yarn with 60 cotton and 40
acrylic in the color seaside blue and i
will be using an h or five millimeter
clover amore crochet hook and we will
also need a yarn needle and some
scissors
and we're going to make five separate
pieces two sleeves one back panel and
two front panels and we're going to
start with the ribbing on one of the
sleeves for all of my ribbing i used the
front post and back post double crochet
but you can make ribbed rows working in
the back loops only
the first thing we'll need is a slip
knot so hold your yarn with the tail end
at the bottom of your hand grab the top
and wrap around two fingers to form an x
and use your hook
to go under
and over
and pull yarn through
remove your fingers
and tighten the knot now we can start
chaining the length around our wrist so
to chain
yarn over and pull through
again yarn over and pull through
so we're going to chain until
this length fits around our wrist but we
are going to make it a little bit longer
so that our whole hand can fit through
and make sure that this is an even
number of chains and once we're done
we're going to chain two more
because we are going to be working
double crochets
i did a total of 28 chains
so now we can start double crocheting
for our first round
and to double crochet
yarn over
insert your hook into the third chain
from your hook
yarn over
pull through
yarn over pull through two loops
then yarn over and pull through your
last two loops and again to double
crochet yarn over insert your hook into
the next chain yarn over pull through
yarn over pull through two loops then
yarn over and pull through two loops and
we're going to continue this all the way
across
so here we have 26 total double crochets
[Music]
we're going to chain two and turn
and for this row we're going to do a
pattern of front post double crochet
back post double crochet then front then
back and front again
and this will give it a ribbed look and
to do a front post double crochet we're
going to yarn over
and then we're going to go behind the
post
of our double crochet and then yarn over
and we're going to pull that through
and then yarn over pull through two yarn
over pull through two
next is the back post double crochet and
we're going to yarn over and we're going
to insert our hook from the back and
then cross over the post of the next
double crochet and then yarn over and
pull through and then we'll yarn over
pull through two
then yarn over pull through two and then
we're going to start over the pattern
with the front post double crochet so
again we're just going to start the
double crochet and insert it in from the
front and complete our double crochet
and for the back post
we're going to start a double crochet
come in through the back and then we're
going to complete our double crochet
again and we're going to continue this
pattern all the way across
and we should end on a back post double
crochet
now we can chain two
turn and start the third row and we're
going to continue this pattern of front
post back post front post back pose all
the way across again
[Music]
and again we should finish in back post
only and you can continue to make more
rows if you want this cuff to be longer
but i am going to stop here and slip
stitch the ends to form a circle
each row will have a slip stitch so i'm
just going to have three slip stitches
so grabbing the other end and making
sure not to twist it i'm going to slip
stitch this closed
and to slip stitch we're going to insert
our hook
under one small loop
on this side and then we'll go under
the entire post on the other end
and then we'll yarn over
pull through
and pull through the loop on your hook
this is a slip stitch and we're going to
do two more so again we're going to go
under a little loop on the side closest
to us and then use our hook to go under
the entire post yarn over pull through
pull through again
and then we'll do that for the last row
[Music]
and it should form this seam and it'll
be
fairly noticeable and we could start
working in the rounds for the rest of
our sleeve we're going to be doing the
lemon peel stitch all around and i'm not
going to do any increases so this first
round is going to be the size for the
entire sleeve so i did need to measure
my gauge for the lemon peel stitch
so i just made a slip knot and chained
until i was a little over four inches
and then i did the lemon peel stitch so
in the second chain from the hook
we're going to do a single crochet
into single crochet
and stitch your hook into the second
chain from the hook
and then yarn over
and pull through
yarn over
and pull through the two loops on your
hook and then we're going to double
crochet into the next chain which we've
already learned but here it is again
yarn over insert your hook into the next
chain yarn over pull through yarn over
pull through just two loops yarn over
pull through two loops this cluster of
one single crochet and one double
crochet is called the lemon peel stitch
so for the next one i'm going to do
another single crochet again insert your
hook yarn over pull through
yarn over pull through your two loops
and then double crochet yarn over insert
your hook yarn over pull through yarn
over pull through two and yarn over pull
through two so here's our second lemon
peel and i'm going to continue this
pattern of single crochets and double
crochets all across my foundation chain
and it turns out that my gauge is 9
lemon peels per 4 inches or 10
centimeters
and with this information i can figure
out how many lemon peels i want in my
sleeve so i want my sleeves to be about
35 centimeters around
so i'm going to
divide 35 by 10
and then multiply it by nine
and this will give me
31.5
lemon peels
but i'm going to round that to a full
lemon peel
so 32
and this is how many lemon peels that
i'll need to get a circumference of 35
centimeters in my sleeve
your gauge may be different from mine
maybe you have 10 lemon peels per 10
centimeters
or eight and
you might want a different size sleeve
and you can do the same calculation just
make sure to not mix up your units
so i wanted 35 centimeters sleeve and i
divided by 10 centimeters not 4 inches
in order to get
32 lemon peels since i have 26 total
stitches i'm going to do one lemon peel
into every single stitch except for
every fourth stitch i'm going to do two
lemon peels
and this will give me 32 total lemon
peels so this might be a little
confusing at first but bear with me
we're going to do our first lemon peel
stitch into the first stitch of this
round so first we're going to chain one
and do one lemon peel into the very
first stitch
[Music]
and then for the next one we'll do one
lemon peel again
[Music]
and for the third one we'll also do just
one lemon peel
[Music]
but for the fourth one we're going to do
two lemon peels so first in our fourth
stitch we're going to do our single
crochet and double crochet
so that's one lemon peel
and then we'll go back into that same
stitch and do another single crochet and
another double crochet
and that's two lemon peels into our
fourth stitch
and we're going to continue this pattern
so for our next three stitches we're
going to do just one lemon peel
and in the fourth we're going to do two
lemon peels
and don't worry if your cuff looks
different from mine it should because i
was trying to test a different method of
starting it
but i prefer the method that i showed
you
every round should end with a double
crochet
a slip stitch and then a chain one
to slip stitch insert your hook into the
very first single crochet that you did
this round
so there should be a little v
at the top of the stitch
go under it with your hook
yarn over
pull through
and then pull through the loop on your
hook
and then we're going to chain one and
turn
i don't usually turn when i do rounds
but
since we're working with the lemon peel
stitch we kind of need to
and it does keep the seam straight
and then we're going to single crochet
on top of our double crochet from last
round
and then in the next stitch we're going
to double crochet on top of the single
crochet from last round
and there are no increases at all so
we're just going to do the lemon peel
stitch all the way around once we get to
the end and it should end with a double
crochet again
we're going to slip stitch
and again to slip stitch
insert your hook under the v of the
first single crochet of this round
yarn over
pull through and pull through the loop
on your hook
and then we're going to chain one and
turn to start round three
and round three is the exact same as
round two we're going to start with a
single crochet
do our lemon peels and end with the
double crochet
slip stitch chain one
turn
and we're just going to be building up
our sleeve until we get the length that
we want
and since this is a big project and i'm
using multiple skeins
here is how you would go about attaching
another ball of yarn
whether it be a single crochet or double
crochet we're going to stop at
two loops on our hook
so i am attaching my yarn on a double
crochet
so now there are two loops left on our
hook
and we're gonna loop our new yarn
onto our hook and pull through those two
loops with our new yarn
and you want to make sure that the tail
end that leaves is also a few inches
long at least
so if you were to do with a single
crochet
all you would do is insert your hook and
pull up a loop and that would already be
two loops on your hook so to finish a
single crochet
loop your new yarn around your hook and
pull through
and my sleeve ended up being about 7
inches or 19 centimeters wide and i
personally wanted sleeves that were a
little short so i did 60 total rounds
which ended up being about 40
centimeters or 15 and a half inches long
and once we're finished with our sleeve
we can fasten off but leave a tail end
long enough for us to sew the sleeve
onto the body and to fasten off after
you slip stitch chain one and then we're
going to cut our yarn pretty long and
it's okay if you end up running out of
yarn to sew your body you can just
attach on a new piece and continue
sewing it's a little hard to estimate
but i'm just going to do double the
length from the top of my shoulder to
the bottom of my cardigan now we can cut
our yarn and use our hook to pull it
through
we can start on the back panel we're
going to be doing a slip knot which we
learned earlier but here it is again
we're going to hold our yarn with the
tail end at the bottom of our hand
grab the top wrap it around two fingers
to form an x
and we're going to use our hook to go
under
and then over
and pull through
remove our fingers and then pull it
tight and we're going to start chaining
the horizontal length that we want our
back panel to be so you want to chain an
odd number and for this part and the
front panels you can use your gauge
to
calculate however many stitches you want
but i did just estimate it
by chaining and then i stopped when the
length of the chain reached from the end
of one shoulder to the end of the other
and this is when i'm not stretching out
the chain i'm just holding it loosely
but just remember that it will tighten
so your chain will become shorter so
just chain a few extra just to be safe
i ended up chaining 73 chains so
starting in our second chain from the
hook we're going to do a single crochet
and then a double and we're going to do
the lemon peel all the way across on our
chain and we should end with a double
crochet in our very last chain if you
did not
make sure that all of your stitches are
correct and if they are then it must
have been the number of chains that you
did was actually even
so you can just remove your last chain
now we can chain one and turn and my
chain one does not count as a single
crochet and then again we're just going
to do the lemon peel stitch all the way
across
and once we get to the end of our second
row with a double crochet
we're going to chain one
turn and do row three
and this is basically just a big
rectangle that we're going to make for
the back panel
and we're going to continue until we get
the length that we want
and i finished the back at 60 rows and
my back panel came out to be about 38
centimeters or 15 inches long and 44
centimeters 17 and a half inches wide
and once we're done
we can fasten off by chaining one
cutting our yarn a few inches long
and then pulling through with our hook
now we can start the front panels
starting the exact same way we did with
the back panel
we're going to make a slip knot
chain
the width of the panel that we want
and you want this to also be an odd
number i did 31 chains
and you want to do the same number of
rows as you made your back panel
so again i did 60 rows
and mine came out to be about 19
centimeters or seven and a half inches
wide
and the same as the back 38 centimeters
or 15 inches long
so this left a six centimeter or two and
a half inch gap between my front panels
and once we're done with our front panel
we can fasten off
but this time leave a long enough strand
for you to sew the tops of the back and
front panels together
and again i'm just going to do double
the length that i have to sew now just
make an identical piece with a long
enough tail end the same length and we
can start putting it together now we're
done with our five pieces and we can
start sewing it together so since the
tail end is
on the left side
i'm going to
flip my piece around so
the back side is facing up
so we can sew it
from right to left
and i like to use the whip stitch
and i'm going to be sewing with the
right sides facing out
to do a whip stitch go under the back
loop of the bottom panel
and then go over
and under the front loop
of the top panel
and we're going to pull our yarn needle
through
and go over to the next stitch
and go under the back loop of the bottom
panel and over and under the front loop
of the top panel
and we're going to continue this
spiraling motion until we finish sewing
the top of the shoulder and once we're
done sewing we can tie a knot by using
our needle to go under a loop
wrapping our yarn around it
and pulling through
and we can leave this loose end to weave
in later
now we're going to do the same thing
with the other front panel
since i did 31 chains for my front panel
i have 30 stitches
so from the left side of my back panel
i'm going to count over
30 stitches
and i'm going to mark my 30th stitch
from the left
with the bobby pin
and i'll get my yarn needle
thread the yarn through
and start whip stitching
first into that stitch that i have my
bobby pin in
[Music]
once we're done we don't need to tie a
knot with our needle there's another
loose end here that we can just double
knot it with
next we're going to be sewing on the
sleeves and i usually like to have the
seam where the slip stitches are facing
down
but since you could barely see the seam
it doesn't really matter
so we're going to start attaching the
sleeve from the bottom
and attach the top of the sleeve to the
top panel
and then go over
behind the sleeve connect that with the
back panel
and then continue connecting the front
panel with the back panel
the first thing you want to do is make
sure that everything is laying flat
and then i'm going to go into the outer
loop on the sleeve and go over and into
just a little loop on the side of the
front panel
and the smaller the piece of yarn that
you go under is
the flatter the seam will be
so i'm just going to constantly go
under just the outer loop on the sleeve
and then into the side of the front
panel here is how it's looking so far
and now we can transition to over the
shoulder and just continue working along
the back of the sleeve and connecting it
with the back panel and once we're done
with the back we can transition to
sewing together the front and back
panels
and once we're done sewing down the side
we can tie a double knot with the tail
end that we left there earlier
and now we can do the exact same thing
with the other sleeve
make sure that everything is laying flat
and it's even on both sides
[Music]
and now that everything is sewn together
here is how it's looking and we can
start working on the ribbing
first we'll do the ribbing on the bottom
of the cardigan
so i'm going to turn the cardigan upside
down
and then i'm going to attach my yarn on
the left side to attach your yarn
just insert your hook
through the first stitch
and then pull your yarn all the way
through
and tie a double knot
and then insert your hook back into that
same stitch and pull up a loop
and then we're going to chain two
and in that same stitch again we're
going to do a double crochet and we're
going to do double crochets all the way
around until we reach the other side now
we will be working into the bottom of
our foundation chain
and instead of going into those same
holes i'm going to go in between two
pieces of yarn just so that the holes
are smaller once we reach the other side
we should have a total of 132
double crochets
and don't worry if your number is a
little off just make sure that it's even
if it's not just add another double
crochet into your last stitch
and now we're going to chain two and
turn
and we're going to be doing the same
ribbing that we did for our sleeve
[Music]
we're going to do a front post double
crochet
[Music]
and then a back post double crochet
and start the pattern over again with a
front post double crochet
and then a back post double crochet
and i'm going to do this until i have
three total rows
and once we're done we can immediately
start working on the ribbing along the
front panels
so first i'm going to turn my work
and then i'm going to chain two
[Music]
we're just going to line the sides of
the front panels and a part of the back
panel with double crochets
making sure to treat them like stitches
and spacing them evenly
once we get to where the front panel
meets the back panel we're going to do a
double crochet three together to soften
the corner
and to double crochet three together
we're going to yarn over
insert our hook into
the side of the corner yarn over pull
through yarn over pull through two and
then yarn over insert our hook into the
corner
yarn over pull through
yarn over pull through two
yarn over insert our hook into the other
side of the corner
yarn over pull through
yarn over pull through two
yarn over pull through all four loops
and then we'll just continue double
crocheting until we reach the other
corner
and here we'll do another double crochet
three together
so we're basically starting another
double crochet before we finish pulling
through the last two loops
so here we'll do three incomplete double
crochets
and in the third one after we've pulled
through two loops we're going to pull
through all four loops
then we'll just work our way down the
other front panel once we get to the end
we'll chain two
turn and start doing our front post and
back post double crochets
i'm going to pause when i get to
one stitch before that double crochet
three together cluster
and i'm going to do a back post double
crochet three together and this is very
similar to the double crochet three
together we're just going around the
posts instead of into the stitches
and we're treating that cluster as just
one stitch so we're going around that
whole cluster
and once i finish this corner i'm going
to do front post into my next stitch
and continue the pattern until i get to
the next corner
and here i'll do a front post double
crochet three together
and i only did a back post double
crochet three together and now a front
post double crochet three together
because that's where it ended up
so you'll just want to continue your own
pattern and it may be slightly different
from mine but that's perfectly fine
and now i'll just work down the side of
the front panel
and complete my second row
so now i'm just going to do this for one
more row and i'll be finished with the
ribbing
now that i'm finished with three total
rows for my ribbing i'm going to chain
one
and cut the yarn
and pull it through with the hook to
fasten off
and now we are very close to being
finished we just need to weave in all of
our loose ends
so the first thing i'm going to do is
pull all of the loose ends to the inside
of the sweater so that i can weave them
in on the inside and they'll be less
visible
and here is how i like to weave in my
loose ends
so first i want to make sure that it's
double knotted and i think i did that
earlier but if yours isn't you can just
use these two strands right next to each
other to tie them in a double knot
and then i'm going to
thread the yarn through the yarn needle
and i'll just go horizontally in one
direction underneath some of the
stitches
[Music]
and then i'll pull my yarn through and
turn around
skip one stitch
and go under those same stitches
this pulls the yarn in two different
directions so it's harder for it to come
out
and if you do end up with a little extra
yarn left you can go back
through those same stitches once more
but i do not so i'm just going to cut
off the excess
and i'll do that same thing for every
single one of my loose ends and now we
are completely finished with this
cardigan i really hope you enjoyed this
tutorial and found it helpful please
leave a like and subscribe if you did
and comment below if you have any
questions at all thank you so much for
watching i'll see you next time
[Music]
you